Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Rohit Deshpande (1) Featured

Associate Solution Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Data Analysis, IT Project Management, Software Design, Shell Scripting, Python, AWS, ML, AI



Current Designation: Associate Solution Engineer- IT Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Current Company: Harman Connected Services

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hubli

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Team lead, Software Development, Software Testing, Data Analysis, IT Project Management, Software Design, Shell Scripting, Python, AWS, Airflow, SQL, Numpy, Pandas, ML, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Software Developer with more than 3 years of experience expertise in planning, coding and testing to provide state of the art software solutions.

Effective communicator with excellent relationship

building and interpersonal skills, possess a flexible and detailed oriented attitude with strong analytical, problem solving and organizational building abilities.

Work Experience

Harman Connected Services as Associate Solution Engineer- IT Sep 2017 to Till Date

Financial Analytics (04/2019 - Present) Collecting and analyzes large amounts of data from different customer?s several data points of various structures. Data collected, transformed and analyzed in the Enterprise Data Lake (Amazon S3) to find different metrics like trial progress, study anomalies, adverse events which helped in making effective business

decisions and devise targeted strategies and as result

improved overall trial experience of user. AWS Data Lake provisioning. Data ingestion pipeline using Python.

Financial News Classification 09/2017 - 03/2019,(9 Months Contract) Creating Python process for web crawling for a bank while extracting daily news for its' counter-parties Post extraction classified news items into High/Low/No impact and displayed in webpage. This helped in getting any early warning to the bank form all of its counterparties. Analyzing various business risk elements in Data Analytics role across BFSI domain. Creating POC?s/POV?s for clients to automate through Machine Learning and NLP in Python and to mitigate

financial risks. https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=cf202d470ca551232616f13255f2e7b55e5800054d160a190519140a5a5a034f415b1... Identifying news areas of business where Machine

Learning can be implemented like News Analytics. Setting up Jobs using Apache Airflow.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from SRI KRISHNA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BANGALORE in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Data Analysis with Python

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
NumPy, Pandas	2020
airflow	2020
AWS	2020
SQL	2020
Linux	2020
Shell Scripting	
Python	2020

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
kannada	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time